I can hear chains falling - chains of affliction.
Satan uses these chains to connect affliction to people - to himself.
That is an instrument;
he uses chains to connect people and that affliction in you is what he is going to use
as a chain to connect you to himself.
But, in this case - I can hear chains falling!
These are his weapons: affliction, poverty, hardship, setback, rejection, challenges.
These are his instruments; these are things he manufactures, and he is using them.
When he sees people happy, with your handset, internet, you suddenly receive a phone call.
"Hello."
The news you hear there can change your heart again.
Before you know it, you begin to be unhappy.
That is the work of satan.
He is now using technology to get people.
When you are stable, suddenly, you will receive a phone call, a text message,
just to make you unhappy.
The state of your heart matters.
The state of my heart matters.
If the state of your heart is at its best – here is Jesus.
If the state of my heart is at its best – here is Jesus.
Now, you can bring Jesus to the scene.
You can say, "In the name of Jesus!“ and Jesus will come, if the state of your heart is at its best
because the Bible says, "Only faith pleases God“.
If only faith pleases God, what is the contact point of faith? Our heart.
Our heart is of faith. Our heart means spirit.
Our heart is the prayer room; our heart is the temple of God.
Today, our heart has become a conflict room between flesh and spirit,
a conflict room between for and against,
a conflict room between good and bad,
a conflict room between humility and pride
and a battleground between good and bad.
If your heart is at its best – here is Jesus.
You can bring Jesus to the scene; you can say, "In the name of Jesus“
and here is Jesus on the scene.
It is simple to know if you are praying.
It is simple to know if I am praying.
You can know if you are praying.
I can't hear you.
I can know if I am praying.
You are just deceiving yourself.
You will know if you are praying or talking to yourself.
How do we know?
We know by our heart, the state of our heart.
I can know if I am praying, and I can know if I am not praying.
So therefore, you can know.
But for you to say, you don’t know whether your prayer will be answered or not,
what kind of person are you?
Our heart is the landing place.
The state of our heart.
If our heart is at its best – that means, free spirit, free heart –
you can say, "Jesus“ - here is Jesus.
A free heart attracts Him.
Where you forget unforgiveness, forget everything behind you,
those who have offended you, those who have wronged you.
You leave all for God.
Then, you can come to God.
Can’t you hear what the Bible says: "Forgive us as we forgive those…“.
How do we forgive without a free heart?
Our Lord’s prayer says, "Forgive us, Lord, as we forgive those who sin against us“.
Is that not what the Bible says?
How can you forgive?
Brother, come here. How can you forgive without a free spirit?
Without a free spirit, you can’t forgive.
Without a free spirit – forget about the Holy Spirit yet.
Holy Spirit is too far. I’m talking to you now.
How can you now forgive without a free spirit?
I can’t forgive, sir.
That is all. It is not possible.
Because everything „Holy Spirit, Holy Spirit!“ – it is too far.
Talk to yourself, your heart.
You cannot forgive without a free heart.
Heart means our spirit. Our spirit means heart.
You cannot forgive.
"Forgive us, as we forgive those who sin against us“ – is that not the covenant we make?
Is that not your covenant? What is your covenant?
The greatest covenant we have made on earth as Christians:
We say to the Lord, "Forgive me, as I forgive those who sin against me“.
That is covenant but we have not fulfilled that covenant.
I will keep coming to church every day, keep praying to God.
That is the first covenant. The second covenant can follow.
The first covenant for Christians all over the world, to become a Christian:
"Forgive me, Lord, as I have forgiven those who have sinned against me".
Have you forgiven those who have sinned against you?
No.
That is why you are struggling, you don’t know whether your prayer is answered,
you don’t know whether you are praying to God.
There is no selection when it comes to forgiveness.
The wrong - the right.
Injustice - justice.
Forgive all.
Whether you are wrong or right, forgive.
Forgive us, as we forgive those who sin against us.
Say to yourself again.
Is that not the covenant you have made?
Is that the first covenant?
That is the first covenant.
Before you come to God, that is the first.
When you open the Bible, the Lord’s prayer is the first to read.
But see what you are doing now.
You are a Christian today but yet, the first thing - one, two - you don’t know.
But you know 100, 1 million; you can count up to that.
Can somebody stand up there and tell me, what your duty now is.
Forgive me, as I forgive those who sin against me.
- What is your duty now?
- To forgive them.
- Who are the people?
- Anybody.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you, brother. My brother says, anybody.
My mummy, ok, come on.
My obligation is that I need to meditate on those words
and God will reveal more to me the people I need to forgive.
So what are the things you have promised initially as a Christian, before you became a Christian?
That I would forgive those who have trespassed against me, as Jesus has forgiven me.
Ok. What has been happening?
To be sincere, what has been happening?
I have been struggling to forgive.
Ok. Will Jesus struggle to bless you?
No.
That is it now. Jesus will struggle to bless you.
I will forgive now.
Help me, Jesus, so that I will forgive all those who have trespassed against me.
Why are you shaking now?
Your heart is troubled because of what?
Pain of the past.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
She said her heart is shaking because of the pain of the past.
So you have seen now.
It is more painful to you than your enemy – unforgiveness;
it is more dangerous to you than your enemy.
Unforgiveness is more dangerous to me than my enemy.
Your enemy needs forgiveness for mercy
but you need forgiveness to [go to] Heaven, [for] eternal life.
Because if you die today without that forgiveness, you are going to hell.
You need it for eternal life but your enemy needs it for favour.
It is more dangerous to you.
So please, take care of yourself. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 14/12/2018
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 24/12/2018